Finding Aid for the Robert Litz papers, 1979-2012
UCLA Library Special Collections
Robert Litz papers
1979-2012
2179
UCLA Library Special Collections
21.75 linear ft. (44 boxes)
Robert Litz was a writer for theater, film, and television. The collection consists of script and project files representing his career.
Litz, Robert
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF. Advance notice is required for access to the collection. Please contact UCLA Library Special Collections for paging information.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Michael Nylan, 2013.
Biography
Robert Litz was born October 3, 1950, in Cleveland, OH. He studied at Boston University and Harvard University. After graduating from Harvard, Litz began working as a press agent and actor for the New England Repertory Theatre in Worcester, MA. In the early 1980s, he began writing plays and became known in 1983 for his play, Great Divide. Throughout his career, Litz wrote 17 produced plays, including Domino, One World, and Mobile Hymn. He also wrote for film and television. His produced screenplays include Rappin' (1985) and House of Cards (1993). His television credits include documentaries written for A&E, History, and Discovery, including the A&E Biography episodes George Washington, Andrew Jackson, and the Emmy-nominated John Travolta. Robert Litz died on October 10, 2012 in Los Angeles, CA.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of theatrical, motion picture, and television script materials and project files representing the career of writer Robert Litz. The bulk of the collection consists of scripts, treatments, and outlines for both produced and unproduced projects. Project files contain notes, research materials, clippings, and ephemera. Some of these files correspond to scripts found in the collection; others relate to television documentary projects. Notably absent from the collection are materials related to the projects, Andrew Jackson and John Travolta.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Personal and Biographical Information
Project Files
Stage Projects
Motion Picture Projects
Television Projects
Book Projects
Essays
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 7314413
Litz, Robert--Archives; Dramatists, American--Archival resources.; Television writers - United States - Archival resources.
Container List
- Personal and Biographical
  - Biographical material., no date. (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Biographical material., 2005 Nov. (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Interviews with Robert Litz., 2006 Dec, 2007 Mar. (Box 15, Folder 4)
- Project Files.
  - 6290 Hollywood Blvd - pitch., no date. (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - 7:39 Club., 1996. (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - 99 and Under., no date. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Action - TV movie treatment., 1983 Sept 9. (Box 37, Folder 18)
  - Ahn Chang Ho - documentary film proposal., no date. (Box 39, Folder 29)
  - Aid and Comfort (Vietnam)., c. 1992. (Box 41, Folder 28)
  - Aladdin., no date. (Box 37, Folder 19)
  - Almost Perfect., 1994 May 2. (Box 41, Folder 26)
  - America House., ca. 2007. (Box 41, Folder 23)
  - American Twist - premise and story., no date. (Box 41, Folder 29)
  - Ancients (The)., ca. 1996. (Box 41, Folder 27)
  - Archangel., no date. (Box 41, Folder 30)
  - Baldy., 1990 Feb. (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Bear and His Monkey (The)., no date. (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Benedict Arnold., 1994, 1999. (Box 41, Folder 32)
  - Benedict Arnold., no date. (Box 41, Folder 31)
  - Benedict Arnold - treatment., no date. (Box 41, Folder 33)
  - Black Days., no date. (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Bloodlines - long treatment., 1995 Mar 10. (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Bob Hope - mini-series project., 1999 May 5. (Box 39, Folder 19)
  - Bobby Robinson - sample., 1988 Jan 13. (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Bright Lighter - treatment proposal., no date. (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Broiler Room (The) - treatment., 1996 Apr 9. (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Bub., ca. 1987. (Box 37, Folder 22)
  - Bub., ca. 1987. (Box 37, Folder 21)
  - Bub., no date. (Box 37, Folder 20)
  - Bunko Squad., no date. (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Campaign of the Century - treatment., no date. (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Case of Rape (A)., no date. (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - Cassatt - teleplay., 1990 Jan. (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Certificate of Copyright Registration forms., 1980s-1990s. (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Chase (The)., no date. (Box 37, Folder 5)
    Also called Enemies Domestic.
  - Cheers., no date. (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - China research., no date. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - China research., no dates. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Chocolate - miniseries., no date. (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Choices - essay., 2000 May. (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Choppers., 1992 Aug. (Box 40, Folder 5)
    Material titled Air Combat II (Episode Four) Vietnam Choppers.
  - Choppers - current draft., no date. (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Christina Onassis., ca. 1991. (Box 35, Folder 16)
    Synopsis of book titled All the Pain That Money Can Buy: The Life of Christina Onassis.
  - Click - treatment., 1985 July 11. (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - Cloak and Dagger., ca. 1994. (Box 42, Folder 14)
  - Code (The)., no date. (Box 42, Folder 15)
  - Colin Powell., no date. (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Confidence Man (The) - treatment for television adaptation., no date. (Box 42, Folder 16)
  - Constitutional Convention., no date. (Box 37, Folder 6)
    Teleplay titled Summer of the Rising Sun.
  - Constitutional Convention - screenplay proposal., 1991 Sept 26. (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Coop., 1990. (Box 42, Folder 17)
  - Coqui., ca. 1985. (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Court (The) - documentary proposal., no date. (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Court (The) - proposal and notes for The Court plays., no date. (Box 36, Folder 33)
  - Cro., no date. (Box 42, Folder 25)
  - Crossing (The) - treatment., 1996 July 1. (Box 42, Folder 26)
  - Crunch., no date. (Box 42, Folder 27)
  - Cry Uncle - a novel., no date. (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - Cults of Doom - documentary., no date. (Box 42, Folder 28)
  - Cup (The)., no date. (Box 42, Folder 29)
  - Cutting Edge II (The)., 1996 Apr 8. (Box 42, Folder 30)
  - Cycles - film., no date. (Box 42, Folder 31)
  - Debs., no date. (Box 42, Folder 23)
  - Delancey Street., 1994. (Box 42, Folder 24)
  - Divine Right., ca. 1989. (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Dolly Dots., ca. 1985. (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Domino., no date. (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Douglas., ca. 1984. (Box 37, Folder 11)
    Part of Supreme Court series.
  - Down River., no date. (Box 42, Folder 21)
  - Down the Road - sitcom., 1993 Nov 24. (Box 42, Folder 18)
  - Downtown., no date. (Box 42, Folder 19)
  - Dramalogue Critics Award for Mobile Hymn., 1997. (Box 42, Folder 20)
  - Duet., 1985 July 8. (Box 42, Folder 22)
  - E.N.G.., no date. (Box 42, Folder 32)
  - Ecks., ca. 1988. (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Elvis and the Colonel - book synopsis., no date. (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Empire - notes., 2005-2006. (Box 41, Folder 25)
  - Euro Flash., ca. 2000. (Box 42, Folder 33)
  - Evangeline., no date. (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - Evangeline/Trust Fund Baby., c. 1990. (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - Exclusion To This Rule., no date. (Box 42, Folder 34)
  - Father Goose - treatment., 1996 July 1. (Box 42, Folder 36)
  - Fighting City Hall., 1995-1996. (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Fighting City Hall., ca. 1996. (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Fire Island., no date. (Box 42, Folder 37)
  - Firefighters - treatment., 1995. (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - First and the Last (The)., no date. (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - First Run - treatment., ca. 1987. (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Flesh - sitcom idea., 1981 Oct 18. (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Fliers., no date. (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Food., ca. 1998. (Box 39, Folder 22)
  - For Better or Worse., c. 1993. (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Four Oaks., no date. (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - Franklin (Benjamin)., no date. (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Getty - book synopsis., no date. (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Global Warming., ca. 2001. (Box 40, Folder 20)
  - Great Divide., no date. (Box 40, Folder 22)
  - Great Divide., 1983. (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Greening of Bobby Parker (The) - treatment., c. 1982. (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Harlan and Sons., no date. (Box 36, Folder 35)
  - High Rolling., 1981, 1983. (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - HISA., 1991 June. (Box 40, Folder 16)
    Material titled Not Far From Here.
  - HISA., no date. (Box 40, Folder 18)
  - Historical Films - essay., no date. (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Hockey., ca. 1993. (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Holmes., ca. 1992. (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Holmes., no date. (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - House of Cards., no date. (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Hub., no date. (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Impeachment., 1998 Nov 1. (Box 43, Folder 11)
    Material titled The Presidency on Trial.
  - Impulse., 1996 July 30. (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - In the Heat of the Night., no date. (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Inside Straight - treatment and sample., 1988 Dec 15. (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - It's a Fairy Tale, Stupid., no date. (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Jackson., no date. (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Japan., no date. (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Jason Ko stories., ca. 1997. (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Jerusalem., 1987. (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Joint Venture., no date. (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Joint Venture., no date. (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - Juarez - outline., no date. (Box 40, Folder 23)
  - Justice (Death Penalty Play)., c. 1992. (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Landmarks., no date. (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - Lee and Grant., no date. (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - Legacy., 1982-1984. (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Legacy (film)., no date. (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Lifetimes., 1986 Sept 1. (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - Little People., no date. (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Los Angeles., 1997 June-July. (Box 39, Folder 21)
  - Louie Louie., ca. 2008. (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Love's Loss., no date. (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Man in the White Suit (The)., ca. 1996. (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Man's Fate., no date. (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Mao., no date. (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Mao, Poster Girl., no date. (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Marshall v. Marshall., ca. 1993. (Box 36, Folder 36)
  - Maxine., 2000. (Box 39, Folder 23)
  - Mayday., c. 1983. (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - Mayo V. - treatment., 1996 Aug 23. (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - McKee Story Structure., no date. (Box 39, Folder 27)
  - McKinnon., no date. (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Me and My Matchmaker., no date. (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - Meter Maids - treatment., 1994 July 27. (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Midnight Movies - pitch., no date. (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Mixed Doubles - screenplay., 1987 Apr 30. (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Mixed Nuts., no date. (Box 41, Folder 22)
  - Mobile Hymn., ca. 1982. (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Mobile Hymn., 1979. (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Mobile Hymn., no date. (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Mobile Hymn - Los Angeles Production., 1997. (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Moby Dick - script pages., no date. (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Mr. Know It All., 2006. (Box 40, Folder 21)
  - Mrs. President and Mother of the President's Child - treatments., no date. (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Mullen poetry., no date. (Box 39, Folder 20)
  - Nat King Cole - pitch., no date. (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - National Pasttime., no date. (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - Nevermore., 1996. (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - New York City Film and Television Productions., no date. (Box 39, Folder 26)
  - Noise in the Night (A)., ca. 1982. (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - Nominee (The)., no date. (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - North Carolina Mutual., 1983. (Box 35, Folder 10)
    Episode of The American Times.
  - Notes from unidentified projects., no date. (Box 37, Folder 4)
    May be related to Supreme Court plays.
  - Nude Dancing., c. 1992. (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Off the Deep End., no date. (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Off the Deep End - notes., 1995 Mar 8. (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Omaha. (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - Onassis., ca. 1991. (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - One Fell Swoop., no date. (Box 41, Folder 20)
  - One Fell Swoop - reviews., 2007 July - Aug. (Box 41, Folder 19)
  - One World., 2004. (Box 43, Folder 19)
  - One World., 2004. (Box 43, Folder 22)
  - One World - reviews., 2004. (Box 43, Folder 20)
  - One World - reviews., 2004. (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - One World - script., no date. (Box 43, Folder 21)
  - Op Domino., c. 1988. (Box 35, Folder 17)
  - Operation Yellowbird - treatment., 1997 Feb. (Box 35, Folder 18)
  - Others., no date. (Box 35, Folder 19)
  - Paine., no date. (Box 35, Folder 20)
  - Pan Am., no date. (Box 35, Folder 21)
  - Paranormal., no date. (Box 39, Folder 18)
  - Perfect Rage (A) - treatment., no date. (Box 35, Folder 22)
  - Pilate., no date. (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Pirate's Daughter (The) - treatment., no date. (Box 35, Folder 33)
  - Poe., ca. 1994. (Box 35, Folder 26)
  - Poisoned Ivy., 1990 Apr 22. (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Ponce de Leon., 1994 Nov 29. (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Powerful Friends., no date. (Box 37, Folder 2)
    Appears related to Justices Louis D. Brandeis and Felix Frankfurter.
  - Prairie Angel - outline., 1986 Apr 28. (Box 35, Folder 32)
  - Presidents - essay on Washington., 1989 Jan 15. (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Primed - outline., 1985 Mar 22. (Box 35, Folder 23)
  - Privilege - script pages., no date. (Box 35, Folder 24)
  - Privilege of the Office., c.1992. (Box 35, Folder 25)
  - Pyramid Club (The)., 1996 Apr. (Box 35, Folder 27)
  - Quartet., no date. (Box 41, Folder 17)
  - Rabbit in the Moon., c. 1992, 1994 Sept 10. (Box 35, Folder 28)
  - Radio Free., no date. (Box 35, Folder 29)
  - Raiders., no date. (Box 35, Folder 30)
  - Ramapo Roulette., no date. (Box 35, Folder 34)
  - Raney - notes., 1987 Mar 25. (Box 35, Folder 31)
  - Red Guitar (The)., no date. (Box 35, Folder 36)
  - Resurrecting Otis - treatment., 2000 Mar. (Box 35, Folder 35)
  - Reviews., 1988, 1995. (Box 36, Folder 32)
  - Riunite - outline for film., 1982 Mar 22. (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Rope of Smoke., no date. (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Run Out - treatment., no date. (Box 35, Folder 37)
  - Run Out - treatment., no date. (Box 35, Folder 38)
  - Safe at Second., ca. 1999. (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Sanctuary., 1990 Jan. (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Satellites., no date. (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Scott and Zelda - notes., no date. (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Scratch., ca. 1999. (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - Screenwriter to the Mob., no date. (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Secret Power (The)., no date. (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Seersucker Whipsaw (The)., 1995 Oct. (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Shajar al-Durr - research and notes., ca. 2009. (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Sherman's March., no date. (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Short Circuits., 1982 Aug 4. (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Short Stories., no date. (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Showdown at Rainbow Creek., no date. (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Silent Partners., no date. (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Smith Painting., 1996 Nov. (Box 40, Folder 19)
  - South of Peace River., c. 1985. (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Southern Ocean., no date. (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - Special Affects., 1985 Oct 10. (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Spenkelink - Date With Eternity., 1992 July. (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Spenkelink - documents., 1992 June. (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Stephen Hawking., no date. (Box 36, Folder 17)
  - Strain., no date. (Box 41, Folder 21)
  - Stuck in Jersey., 1997 Feb 1. (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Sullivan's Travels - remake proposal., no date. (Box 36, Folder 18)
  - Sullivan's Travels - remake proposal., 1996 Mar 1. (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Super 8. (Box 36, Folder 20)
  - Supremes (The) - treatment., ca. 2009. (Box 36, Folder 34)
  - Swashbuckle., no date. (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Swoozie., no date. (Box 36, Folder 19)
  - Synopses., no date. (Box 39, Folder 28)
  - T.J. Maxwell mysteries., 2002. (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - Tangles., no date. (Box 36, Folder 27)
  - Tango Run - synopsis., 1986 Oct 14. (Box 36, Folder 23)
  - Television Movies., 1998-1999. (Box 39, Folder 25)
  - Tenants (The) - sample., 1987 Jan 30. (Box 36, Folder 25)
  - Terror., c. 1991. (Box 36, Folder 21)
  - Test Run - outline., no date. (Box 36, Folder 22)
  - T-Floor., no date. (Box 36, Folder 29)
  - T-Floor - synopsis., 1985 Sept 22. (Box 36, Folder 24)
  - Theory and Practice of Oligarchical Collectivism (The)., no date. (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Thoreau/Walden., no date. (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Those Who Stayed., c. 1982. (Box 36, Folder 26)
    Rhode Island Retrospective: Episode One, King Philip's war Spring 1676.
  - Those Who Stayed., c. 1982. (Box 36, Folder 30)
  - Three Acts for Three Women., no date. (Box 36, Folder 28)
  - Ties - treatment., c. 1986. (Box 36, Folder 31)
  - Tragedy of Man - feature film treatment., 1988 Nov 20. (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Trampling Vineyards., no date. (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Translating Confucius. (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Treatments., no date. (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Tumblers - notes for novel., no date. (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Two Ships Passing., no date. (Box 39, Folder 24)
  - Unidentified holographic notes., no date. (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Unidentified project (file label illegible)., no date. (Box 42, Folder 35)
  - Unidentified projects., no date. (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Unidentified stage project., no date. (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Upcountry., no date. (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Venona - pitch., no date. (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Vera Mouse., 1998. (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Virginia Story (Prayer in Schools)., no date. (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Waiting to Be Free - treatment., no date. (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Waking Frank Rice., no date. (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Walden., no date. (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - War Dog., no date. (Box 41, Folder 18)
  - Warrior Way (The)., ca. 1995. (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Washington., ca. 1994. (Box 40, Folder 1)
    Material titled George Washington: Father of a Country.
  - Weatherman., no date. (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - Weehawken: The Final Years of Alexander Hamilton - treatment., no date. (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - West Palm., 1995 June 30. (Box 41, Folder 14)
  - Westmoreland and Giap., 1993 May. (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Whittier Talk., 2002 Oct 14. (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Wild Card., 1982 Apr 7. (Box 41, Folder 15)
  - Will Work 4., no date. (Box 41, Folder 24)
  - Winners' Circle., 1995 June 30. (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Winner's Circle - opening and treatment., no date. (Box 41, Folder 16)
  - Wright Brothers., no date. (Box 41, Folder 10)
- Stage Projects.
  - America House., 2007 Dec. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Back Pay., 2008 July 4. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Back Pay., 2010 Apr 2. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Back Pay - pitch., no date. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Blood of Our Fathers., 2011 Sept 6. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Blood of Our Fathers., 2011 Sept 6. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Part of Supreme Court Series.
  - Blood of Our Fathers., 2010 Apr 21. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Bub., 2008 June. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Bub., 2007 Feb 20. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Clover., no date. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Clover., 1989 Apr. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Compensation., 2009 Mar 10. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Cycles., no date. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Cycles., no date. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Cycles., ca. 2012. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Devil's Bargain (The)., 2006 Oct 21. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Domino., c. 1998. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Domino., c. 1987. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Douglas., c. 1983. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Douglas., no date. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Edgar., 1994 Dec 1. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Empire., 2008 Apr 20. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Empire., 2007 Aug 2, no date. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Enemies Domestic., 2010 Apr 21. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Fit to Print., no date. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Fit to Print., no date. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Flare., 2012 Feb 17. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Flare., 2012 Feb 17. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Flare., 2012 Feb 8. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Free Bird., 2012 Apr 11. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Free Bird., 2011 Apr 20. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Free Bird., 2012 Sept 15. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Free Bird., 2012 July 4. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Free Bird., 2012 July 4. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Great Divide., no date. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Great Divide., no date. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - High-Rolling., 1982 May 30. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Hot Mix., c. 1979. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Hot Mix., 2007 July 22. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Jumpers., 2007 Dec 1. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Lincoln., 2000 Feb - Mar. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Long Beach., no date. (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Long Beach., 2010 Sept 18. (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Mamagrace., no date. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Mamagrace., 2008 Nov 17. (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Marshall v. Marshall., 2012 Mar 29. (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Mary's Fault., c. 1983. (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Mixed Nuts., no date. (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Mobile Hymn., 1985 Sept 20. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Mobile Hymn., 1997 June 1. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Mobile Hymn., no date. (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Mobile Hymn., 2005 May 5. (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Mobile Hymn., no date. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Mobile Hymn - publicity., 1997 June-July. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - No Stopping Anytime., c. 1983. (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Oliver Wendell Holmes., no date. (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Oliver Wendell Holmes., 2009 June. (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - One Fell Swoop., 2007. (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - One Fell Swoop., 2007 July 13. (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - One Fell Swoop., 2007. (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - One World., 2004 May 20. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - One World., 2004 Aug 1. (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - One World., ca. 2004. (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - One World., 2004 Aug 1. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Others., no date. (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Pilgrims in Vienna., 2006, 2008. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Pilgrims in Vienna., no date. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Pitches for various stage projects., no date. (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Rachel Variant (The)., 2011 Sept 2. (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Rachel Variant (The)., 2006 July 13. (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Rachel Variant (The)., 2012 Feb 21. (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Rachel Variant (The)., no date. (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Rachel Variant (The)., 2006 July 13. (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Rope of Smoke., c. 1988. (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Rope of Smoke., 2008 Apr. (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Rope of Smoke., no date. (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Rustbelt., 2009 Sept 28. (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Seat at the Table (A)., no date. (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Seat at the Table (A)., 2011 Sept 1. (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Seat at the table (A)., 2009 Sept 21. (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Seat at the Table (A)., 2012 July 4. (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Seed., 2011 Mar. (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Seed., no date. (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Seed., 2011 May 24. (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Seed., 2011 Mar, May. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Sentimientos No Se Tocan (Los) - Playing in Thirds., 2010 Oct 31. (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Shores of Kilimanjaro - [pitch]., no date. (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Sliding Past Home., no date. (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Sliding Past Home., no date. (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Sliding Past Home., ca. 2002. (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Tipping Point., 2011 June, Sept. (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Tipping Point., 2012 July 10. (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Tipping Point., no date. (Box 30, Folder 7)
    Appears to be related to Tipping Point.
  - Tipping Point., 2011 Oct 26. (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Trampling Down the Vineyards., 2010 Feb 20. (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Twelve Americans., 2005 Apr 5. (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Twelve Americans., 2010 Apr 27. (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Twelve Americans., 2005 Feb 24. (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Upcountry., no date. (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Waiting Room (The)., 2006 July 15. (Box 33, Folder 5)
- Motion Picture Projects.
  - Aladdin., 1985 Sept 20. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Algo Rythm., 1995 Nov 10. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - American Woman: The Story of Julie Hiatt Steele - treatment., no date. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Ancients (The)., 1997 Apr. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - As You Love Me., no date. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Bargain (The)., 1996, 1999. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Also known as Impulse.
  - Bear and His Monkey (The)., ca. 2005. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Bear and His Monkey (The)., no date. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Big Dog., 2009 May 5. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Big Dog - treatment., no date. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Big Man., ca. 1999. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Breakfast Included., 2008 May 12. (Box 4, Folder 2)